Guide to the Harlan B. Brumsted papers, 1998-2003.
Brumsted, Harlan B. papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Harlan B. Brumsted papers, 1950s-1999.
21-18-3257
Harlan B. Brumsted
41.7 cubic ft.
Correspondence, course materials, subject files, publications, tape recordings, slides, and ephemera.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes subject files, correspondence, publications, pertaining to Brumsted's career in the Dept. of Natural Resources.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Natural Resources, Cornell University.
Harlan Brumsted received a B.A. from Dartmouth College and an M.S. and Ph.D from Cornell University. He began teaching at Cornell in 1954, with responsibility for Extension programs in wildlife management, aquatic management, natural resources conservation, and outdoor recreation.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes subject files, correspondence, course materials, publications, slides, and tape recordings pertaining to Brumsted's career in the Dept. of Natural Resources.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Brumsted, Harlan B.; Cornell University--Faculty.; New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences. Dept. of Natural Resources.
Form and Genre Terms:
Slides (photographs).; Audiotapes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence (1 of 3), December 1975-January 1983; February 1984-June 1985 (Box 1)
- Correspondence (2 of 3), December 1970-January 1974 (Box 2)
- Correspondence (3 of 3), December 1964-January 1969; 1954-1956; 1960-1963 (Box 3)
- New York State Legislative Commission, 1970s (Box 4)
- American Wildlife Research Foundation, 1980s-1990s (Box 4)
- Cornell Calender Prepared by Harlan B. Brumsted and Ray T. Oglesby, 1998-1999 (Box 4)
- Department of Natural Resources (1 of 10), 1960s-1980s (Box 5)
- Department of Natural Resources (2 of 10), 1950s-1970s (Box 6)
- Department of Natural Resources (3 of 10), 1973-1978 (Box 7)
- Department of Natural Resources (4 of 10), 1963-1987 (Box 8)
- Department of Natural Resources (5 of 10), 1960s-1970s (Box 9)
- Department of Natural Resources (6 of 10), 1950s-1960s (Box 10)
- Department of Natural Resources (7 of 10), 1960s-1970s; 1990s (Box 11)
- Department of Natural Resources (8 of 10), 1970s-1980s (Box 12)
- Department of Natural Resources (9 of 10), 1980s-1990s (Box 13)
- Department of Natural Resources (10 of 10), 1950s; 1980s (Box 14)
- Outdoor Recreation Enterprise Development Program (1 of 4), 1960s-1970s (Box 15)
- Outdoor Recreation Enterprise Development Program (2 of 4), 1960s-1970s (Box 16)
- Outdoor Recreation Enterprise Development Program (3 of 4), 1970s (Box 17)
- Outdoor Recreation Enterprise Development Program (4 of 4); Proposed Conservation Education Project (1950s); Two Wildlife Administration Law and Policy Reserve Notebooks (1960s); Design and Development of a Science Program for Elementary and Junior High School Grades (1962); Job completion report "Study of Conditions Influencing Year Class Strength of Walleyes in Oneida Lake (1963-1964): Plan for a National Program of Fish and Wildlife Extension Education (1977); Plan for a Dept. of Natural Resources Extension Program (1985), 1960s-1980s (Box 18)
- Credit Courses Taught - 3 weeks, 3 credits (1 of 6), 1962 (Box 19)
- Credit Courses Taught (2 of 6), 1970s-1980s (Box 20)
- Credit Courses Taught - #410 (3 of 6), 1970s-1980s (Box 21)
- Credit Courses Taught - #410, 412, 414 (4 of 6), 1970s-1980s (Box 22)
- Credit Courses Taught - #414, 490, 601, 604 (5 of 6), 1970s-1980s (Box 23)
- Credit Courses Taught (6 of 6), 1970s-1980s (Box 24)
- New York State Fish and Wildlife Management Act (1 of 2), 1960s-1970s (Box 25)
- New York State Fish and Wildlife Management Act (2 of 2), 1980s (Box 26)
- Community Resource Development (1 of 9), 1960s (Box 27)
- Community Resource Development (2 of 9), 1960s (Box 28)
- Community Resource Development (3 of 9), 1960s (Box 29)
- Community Resource Development (4 of 9), 1960s (Box 30)
- Community Resource Development (5 of 9), 1960s-1980s (Box 31)
- Community Resource Development (6 of 9), 1950s-1960s (Box 32)
- Community Resource Development (7 of 9), 1960s (Box 33)
- Community Resource Development (8 of 9), 1960s (Box 34)
- Community Resource Development (9 of 9), 1960s-1971 (Box 35)
- Non CALS Programs (1 of 2), 1970s-1980s (Box 36)
- Non CALS Programs (2 of 2), 1960s-1970s (Box 37)
- Extension Agents In-service Education Program (1 of 2), 1954; 1960s-1970s; 1980-1982 (Box 38)
- Extension Agents In-service Education Program (2 of 2), 1982-1984 (Box 39)
- Sportsman's Workshop (1 of 2), 1951-1969 (Box 35)
- Sportsman's Workshop (2 of 2), 1963-1978 (Box 40)
- Cooperative Extension as an Institution, 1960s-1970s (Box 41)
- Southwestern New York - All Vegetable Wildlife and Allegany State Park Studies, 1962-1972 (Box 42)
- Slides-Biology and Society - Cranch and Wilkins, Fall 1971 (Box 43)
- Slides and Cassette Tape - Understanding Lakes and Lake Problems, no date (Box 43)
- Cassette Tape- Director Smith's Seminar - "Extension and E.Q." (Agricultural Engineering), April 1972; tr 9903 (Box 43)
- Cassette Tape - Senior Practicum, no date; tr 9904 (Box 43)
- Reel to Reel Tape - Biology and Society Lectures- live and dubbed from radio, no date; tr 9905 (Box 43)
- Reel to Reel Tape - Hearing and Meetings in Albany, no date; tr 9906 (Box 43)
- Reel to Reel Tape - Cranch, September 1971; tr 9907 (Box 43)
- Reel to Reel Tape - Education Commission, no date; tr 9907 and tr 9908 (Box 43)
- Reel to Reel Tape - New York and Albany Meetings, no date; tr 9909 (Box 43)
- Reel to Reel Tape - Panel Discussion, October 1971; tr 9910 (Box 43)
- Reel to Reel Tape - D. Ludington "A Wasteful Society; A Waste-Filled Land", October 1970; tr 9911 (Box 43)
- Reel to Reel Tape, October 1971; tr 9912 (Box 43)
- Reel to Reel Tape - New York and Albany Meetings, no date; tr 9913 (Box 43)